[Music]
hello and welcome to the GP enhancement
migration session my name is Casey Meer
and today I'll be talking about many of
the new and exciting enhancements that
we have made to the GP migration tool as
part of Wave 2
2022 today I want to spend some time
talking about the changes that we made
to the migration Setup Wizard we took
some of the options that you had
available there and made them into a new
GP configuration page giv you much more
flexibility in choosing what you want to
migrate to business Central I also want
to give a refresher on many of the new
enhancements that we've added in the
last few months as well as give you a
sneak peek into what you can expect as
the new release comes out
finally we'll take a closer look at the
tool itself as well as the data that we
are going to migrate from your GP on
Prem system into business Central so as
I mentioned many of you are familiar
with the existing migration tool Setup
Wizard where you had just a few options
to migrate it was really an All or
Nothing approach you either had to
choose to bring all your data over with
a few options to not bring over inactive
information what we've done now is taken
that information out of the setup Wizard
and created a new configuration page
where you have many more options to
choose for what you want to bring over
from your GP system into business
Central you can choose things like which
modules you want to bring over if you
want to bring over certain Master data
records you can choose all of that so
you'll find that the page gives you much
more flexibility it also has Global
controls letting you select for all the
companies that you want to migrate or
you can make those individual selections
at the company
level I also mentioned I wanted talk
about a bit of the new features that
have comeing in the last few months
we've added many new things like being
able to choose to not migrate your in
the active checkbooks or your bank
accounts we know many GP customers have
old bank accounts that they don't want
to bring over to their to their business
Central environment so you can choose
not to bring that information over you
can also bring over your unreconciled
bank transactions previously in order to
migrate you needed to reconcile your
bank accounts before migrating now all
those unre reconciled transactions will
come over for you so you can reconcile
after your
migration we've also added the ability
to bring over your fiscal period
information so you don't need to reset
up your accounting periods in business
essential that fiscal period information
will come over for you as well as if
you've set up bank account information
for your vendors again that information
will automatically migrate over we also
know that many GP customers like the
class concept so they'll put classes
together for their customers items
vendors and then posting accounts
associated with those so now you'll have
the option if you want to bring that
information over as posting groups into
business Central and those customers
items and vendors will be assigned to
their appropriate classes and finally we
also give you the ability to limit the
number of GL years that you want to
bring over many GP customers have been
on the system for 10 15 20 years and
don't want to bring all that information
over into business Central so you can
easily enter in the year that you want
to bring and everything from that year
forward will come over into your
business Central environment so I
encourage you if you haven't looked at
the tool in a while take a look at it
look at some of these new features that
have been added and then as part of Wave
2 2022 what you can expect is that new
GP configuration page I mentioned giv
you a lot more flexibility being able to
pick and choose the information you want
to bring over you can select which
modules you want to bring over perhaps
you just want to bring your GL and AP
information over and leave some of your
receivables back in GP you can you can
choose to do that you can also pick if
you want to just bring Master data over
for each module um as well as being able
to pick if you don't want to bring over
your discontinued or inactive items many
GP customers have hundreds if not
thousands of items in their inventory
many which could be inactive or
discontinued and don't want to bring
that information over to business
Central so you can choose to do that
also based on some feedback we bring
over that g uh summary information over
migrated over but everything was being
assigned with the same document number
which made it difficult to reconcile or
if you needed to reverse a specific
transaction it was reversing everything
so now we will increment that document
number for those individual GL summary
records so that is a sneak peek into
what you can expect as part of the new
release with that let's dig into the
tool in a bit more
detail so let's go ahead and jump into
the GP migration tool you can still
access the tool like you always have by
going up to the search and I'm going to
type in that migration management
wizard here is my cloud migration setup
so the wizard is just as it was before
where you can come in and select your
options around the privacy policy and on
the next screen is where you can select
your GP migration tool this next screen
again is where you create that secure
connection between your GP on Prem
system into your business Central SAS so
it will use the aure aure migration data
Factory to move that information
securely across the next screen there's
only one left is where you pick the
companies that you want to migrate from
your GP system into business Central
since that step takes a few moments
we'll go ahead and close out of the
setup Wizard and once you are done going
through the wizard the new GP
configuration page will automatically
open for you you can also access it from
the migration management page which
where we will go next so in the cloud
migration management page there will be
a new option that you can select called
configure GP migration and in this
window you will see there's a lot more
options allowing you to pick and choose
the type of information that you want to
move from your GP system into business
Central the first option are the modules
so by default they are all turned on so
you can migrate all the modules but if
there are specific modules you don't
want to bring over into business Central
you can go ahead and toggle them off for
example let's say you just track a few
customers in your GP system and you want
to start fresh in business Central so
I'm going to go ahead and uh un unmark
or toggle off receivables and not bring
that information over into business
Central the next option is if you just
want to bring your master data record
over now by default these are all off so
Master data and transaction information
will come over but maybe in this case
you just want to bring your bank account
information over but not any transaction
information so I'll say I only want to
bring Master data over for bank then
next area is where you can choose that
inactive record information you've
always been able to select if you don't
want to bring over inactive customers or
vendors but now with new enhancements
you can choose to not bring over
inactive checkbooks and very soon you'll
be able to pick if you don't want to
bring over inactive items or
discontinued items and in this case I'm
not going to bring over our old inactive
or discontinued
items the next area are the classes I
mentioned earlier if you were big users
of classes in GP you you can still bring
that information over into business
Central as posting groups so I'm going
to go ahead and bring over my vendor
classes what that will do is create uh
posting groups for each one of my vendor
classes and assign the appropriate
vendors to those with the right accounts
now I mentioned these settings are all
at a global level so if you've selected
to migrate several companies these
options will apply to all of those
companies however at the bottom you can
tweak per company so in the setup wizard
I chose to migrate two companies over
and you can see the selections I've made
above are available down below and I can
tweak it at a company level let's say
for this first company limit company I
don't want to bring over my payables
information so I don't want that AP
information to come over so I'm going to
go and unmark my AP option there I can
also scroll over and see that it's
automatically unmarked the vendor
classes so if the options are correlated
or have a relationship they will be
unmarked when you unmark one of the
other ones
the next option that you want to do is
set your Global Dimensions up now if you
remember business Central uses
Dimensions instead of the segments so
your segments in GP will get migrated
over as Dimensions whatever main account
segment that you have set up in GP will
come over as your main account or
natural account in business Central and
then you need to choose which of your
next two segments you want to be as
Global Dimensions the remaining segments
will come over as shortcut Dimensions so
if you are migrating a lot of companies
that have similar Dimensions we suggest
that you come up to the set all
Dimensions this will allow you to select
your Dimensions once so I'm going to say
my department segment is going to be my
first Global Dimension and my division
segment is going to be my next Global
Dimension what that will do is when I
click okay it will apply to any company
that uses those same same segments now
you can see it didn't default in for my
limit company because those two segments
don't exist for that company so I just
need to come back in and select which
segments I want to be the global
Dimension one and two for that
particular
company lastly I mentioned that you can
now limit the amount of GL summary
information that you bring into business
Central by default we default it to zero
which means it's going to bring
everything over from your GP system all
that summary information for all the
years will automatically come over to
business Central but let's say I've got
10 or 15 years out there and I don't
want all of that information to business
Central I just want the last few years
so I can go ahead and type in a year so
I'm going to type in 2020 for both my
companies and what that will do is it'll
bring that year and everything forward
over it'll also create your beginning
balances for 2020 so it'll look at 2019
transactions create those beginning
balances for you in 2021 or in 2020 and
then bring all of that information over
so you can see there's a lot of new
selections available to here all your
information is saved if you need to make
some changes in this it has saved all of
that you can come back in and out as you
um talk to others in your organization
if you're a partner and you talk to your
customer you can come back in once
you're happy with all of your options
you can come back out and then that's
where you start your migration process
as you've done before the first step is
to run the migration now which takes all
of the information from your GP tables
moves those into staging tables once
that's done then you run the upgrade
which takes the information from your
staging tables transer forms that and
then brings it into the actual business
Central table so that steps um are the
same from version or wave 1 2022 those
two steps were there um this is just
adding that GP configuration option uh
right in the beginning give you that
increased flexibility so let's take a
look I've run the migration so let's
jump over to a company that was actually
migrated and look at what the data looks
like in that company so if I jump over
into my fabric cam company this is that
demo company that you see in GP and
let's take a look at some of the data
that I migrated over if you remember in
that GP configuration page I chose not
to bring over my AR or my receivables
information so once I get into this
company I wouldn't expect to see any of
my customers from GP and you can see I
don't have any customers CU I chose not
to bring that receivables information
over I did however choose to bring over
my payables or my AP information so if I
click under vendors I should see all all
of the vendors that were in my GP system
I can see all of them here I've got all
their balance information so the
migration tool will automatically bring
over all of those open invoices so I can
start and continue to pay any
outstanding invoices that I have with my
vendor in business
Central if you remember I also wanted to
bring over that class information so I
had my vendors assigned to classes in GP
so if I drill into my vendor and I
scroll down I can see now my vendor
posting groups this was the class that
it was assigned to in GP so I have all
those classes over in business Central
now if I click on the drop- down again
these are all of those GP classes
available what is nice is many of the
reports in business Central you can
easily filter on those posting groups so
if I go under reports and go to my trial
balance for example I can easily filter
my trial balance on those classes again
so if you were using classes quite a bit
in GP you can still use that same
similar Concept in business
Central in addition to my AP information
if you remembered I chose in bank that I
just wanted to bring over my master data
so if we go over to bank accounts I
should see all the bank accounts that
were set up in my GP system but I just
said bring over Master data so that's
why I don't have balances or
transactions in here but I could easily
enter in that beginning balance whatever
my current balance is in my bank account
quickly enter those in so that's just an
example where you may just want to bring
in master data but not that transaction
information one last thing I did want to
show you is that accounting information
those fiscal periods do come over as
your accounting periods so if we go in
and type in my accounting
periods I should see all the information
for my fiscal periods in that were set
up in GP now in business Central and I
no longer need to manually enter in all
of that information so again and it will
take that fiscal period information and
bring it over into your accounting
periods and that's a quick look at all
the enhancements we made to the GP
migration tool in the last few months
and what you can expect to see in wave
2022 thank you for joining today and I
encourage you to check out the many
other sessions that are available in the
launch event thank
you